<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>css on Ghassan&#39;s Page</title>
    <link>https://www.ghassan.page/tags/css/</link>
    <description>Recent content in css on Ghassan&#39;s Page</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2015 19:51:56 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.ghassan.page/tags/css/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>CSS Fonts</title>
      <link>https://www.ghassan.page/posts/2015_11_26_css_fonts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2015 19:51:56 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ghassan.page/posts/2015_11_26_css_fonts/</guid>
      <description>The simplist way to use different fonts in your web site is using fonts from the &amp;ldquo;Web-Safe&amp;rdquo; fonts[1] [2].&#xA;But, no impressive design will depend only on these web-safe fonts, and designers add their own preferable fonts to the web site they are building.&#xA;How to add your preferable fonts?Fonts comes as files that you have to upload to the site, and then reference them in the CSS file.&#xA;Usually font vendors provide fonts with different formats in order to be consumable by many different browsers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CSS Reset</title>
      <link>https://www.ghassan.page/posts/2015_11_18_css_reset/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2015 19:51:56 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ghassan.page/posts/2015_11_18_css_reset/</guid>
      <description>Every web developer had an experience where he test his web site on Chrome, IE and FireFox, to find out that the experience is a little bit different, because browsers have their own default implementation and rendering for the HTML elements. Which means if you don&amp;rsquo;t overwrite the default implementation with your own CSS rules, then the browser will use its own implementation.&#xA;If you are very keen on making the exact same user experience between all browsers even with the smallest details, then the community came up with a technique called &amp;ldquo;CSS Reset&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
